Enrique Olmedo González

Santiago/Chile | +569 9888 9881 eolmedogonzalez@gmail.com

in linkedin

SUMMARY

Head of Business Intelligence with 6+ years of data analysis experience. Proficient in Python and SQL. Experience working with different statistical and ML models applying them to different real life scenarios. I've helped my company to reduce costs by 10% and increase prices by 22% using some of these models. I'm passionate for data science and learning. Master's Degree in Industrial Engineering. Bachelor's Degree in Science. Fluent english. Native spanish.

EXPERIENCE

POLPAICO BSA

April 2015 - Present

HEAD OF BUSINESS INTELLIGENCE | UNE 2019 - PRESENT

Created pricing statistical model and lead its implementation nationwide | Created model to predict quote winning probability | Continuously check for pricing opportunities and update prices in SQL Server tables | Code and implement pricing application updates (C#) Generate insights from data | Create automated reports | Automated pricing for new products

HEAD OF PROCESS OPTIMIZATION APRIL 2018 - JUNE 2019

Generate concrete cement dose optimization model | Lead ETL processes for data analysis | Automate dose consistency checking

PROCESS OPTIMIZATION ENGINEER SEPTEMBER 2017 - JUNE APRIL 2018

Generate reports on concrete strength | ETL data from multiple sources for data analysis | Create case simulations in python for decision making |

OPERATIONS ANALYST APRIL 2015 - SEPTEMBER 2017

Implement operational process control system | KPI reporting and dashboards | Control and optimization of costs tied to the operation.

SYNCHRONIC CONSULTING

September 2020 - Present

FOUNDER

Personal company where we offer IT services to small and medium sized businesses.

Services we have done: web development, CRM configuration, report and process automation and system and software recommendation.

SKILLS

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES Experienced: Python | SQL Familiar: Javascript | R | C# | HTML | CSS

FRAMEWORKS & LIBRARIES Jupyter | Matplotplib | Numpy | Pandas | Tensorflow | openCV | NodeJS | GIT

LANGUAGES Native: Spanish Fluent: English

EDUCATION

UNIVERSIDAD DE CHILE 2020

BUSINESS INTELLIGENCE AND BIG DATA DIPLOMA

UNIVERSIDAD ADOLFO IBÁÑEZ 2017-2018

MASTER'S DEGREE IN INDUSTRIAL ENGINEERING

Universidad de Chile 2008-2016

BACHELOR'S DEGREE IN SCIENCE, GEOLOGY MAJOR

COURSES AND SPECIALIZATIONS

• Big Data & Business Analytics Course at U. Católica de Chile | Data Science Specialization at IBM Coursera

EXTRA

• 2nd place at Ultrahack (2021): a Hackathon organized by Finland's Embassy to create projects based on Artificial Intelligence and Data Science to fight against Climate Crisis and Environment related problems.